<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Silent Action</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/silent-action-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/silent-action-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Actions taken to accomplish good works should be done without seeking attention.
 Sometimes attention is unavoidable but it should be reduced to the minimal amount needed to get the work done or to what will maximize the impact of the act.
Everything else above this minimized amount is performative and serves no other purpose than self-aggrandizement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Team Skill</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/small-team-skill-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:20:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/small-team-skill-1-0/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important skills a small team can collectively have is the ability to identify what they don&amp;rsquo;t need to build for a minimum viable product (&amp;ldquo;MVP&amp;rdquo;).
Smaller teams inherently have fewer human resources available to build things and must prioritize. An open two-way dialogue between the team and the customer helps identify the core value the product provides the customers. With this the team can provide that initial core value in their MVP even if it&amp;rsquo;s held together with rubber bands and bubble gum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Decisions</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-decisions-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 08:41:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-decisions-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The individuals best suited for making decisions on any solution are those closest to the problem. It is the leader&amp;rsquo;s only job to facilitate these decisions. A leader should:
 Provide guidance when it is requested Arbitrate disputes when they arise Make decisions when presented options Spread vision and purpose when leading  Leaders should work to empower individuals to make their own decisions and only impose their own when absolutely necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War King</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/war-king-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:45:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/war-king-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The king who avoids war at all costs is the king to avoid in war.
 Those who are passionate for peace will passionately pursue its return.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
