<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://johnforstmeier.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adversity Figures</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/adversity-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/adversity-figures/</guid>
      <description>Anecdotally to the observer, it seems that national adversity produces heroes while personal adversity produces victims.
 Why is there a perceived difference and why can&amp;rsquo;t personal adversity produce public heroes?
 In national-level issues, everyone is impacted and all shoulder the burden while a few rise as leaders. For example, in World War II individuals such as Churchill [1], Murphy [2], Winters [2], and Sendler [4] are rightfully treated as heroes for their noble defense of freedom even as the conflict touched all lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Capital Preference</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/social-capital-preference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/social-capital-preference/</guid>
      <description>Some companies rely heavily on social capital as part of their continued financial success. To varying degrees, this makes them dependent on current social trends.
However, even companies that are not overly impacted by social perception (e.g. ones with strong customer stickiness) seem to seek it out. In doing so they appear to voluntarily relinquish an advantageous position.
 Why take on an unnecessary dependency?
 Maybe there is or always has been a strong need to &amp;ldquo;belong&amp;rdquo; even in profit-driven enterprises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Bad Blood</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reading-bad-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reading-bad-blood/</guid>
      <description>This piece is on Bad Blood [1] by John Carreyrou [2].
I was familiar with the story of Elizabeth Holmes [3] and her company Theranos [4] but the book provided greater insight into how she interacted with people regarding her work.
It is unclear whether her extreme focus on &amp;ldquo;her mission&amp;rdquo; was a manipulative effort or actual self-denial; her actions could support both positions.
There are many instances of Holmes legally pursuing whistleblowers and publicly attacking external detractors - essentially anyone threatening the positive perception of Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Action</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/silent-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/silent-action/</guid>
      <description>Actions taken to accomplish good works should be done without seeking attention.
 Sometimes attention is unavoidable but it should be reduced to the minimal amount needed to get the work done or to what will maximize the impact of the act.
Everything else above this minimized amount is performative and serves no other purpose than self-aggrandizement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Team Skill</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/small-team-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:20:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/small-team-skill/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important skills a small team can collectively have is the ability to identify what they don&amp;rsquo;t need to build for a minimum viable product (&amp;ldquo;MVP&amp;rdquo;).
Smaller teams inherently have fewer human resources available to build things and must prioritize. An open two-way dialogue between the team and the customer helps identify the core value the product provides the customers. With this the team can provide that initial core value in their MVP even if it&amp;rsquo;s held together with rubber bands and bubble gum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Decisions</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/facilitating-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 08:41:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/facilitating-decisions/</guid>
      <description>The individuals best suited for making decisions on any solution are those closest to the problem. It is the leader&amp;rsquo;s only job to facilitate these decisions. A leader should:
 Provide guidance when it is requested Arbitrate disputes when they arise Make decisions when presented options Spread vision and purpose when leading  Leaders should work to empower individuals to make their own decisions and only impose their own when absolutely necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War King</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/war-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:45:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/war-king/</guid>
      <description>The king who avoids war at all costs is the king to avoid in war.
 Those who are passionate for peace will passionately pursue its return.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>