<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 15:10:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Equity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/reverse-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 15:10:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/reverse-equity/</guid>
      <description>Issuing equity in the company to employees is a common method employers use to distribute compensation. Shares can be distributed publicly or privately and most of the time they represent a literal voting ownership of the enterprise. When treated as compensation, equity is typically issued via a vesting schedule to the employees in question.
Equity differs from other compensation methods the most widespread of which, in my estimation, is a common salary or wage over some fixed or non-fixed distribution periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Modern Distributism</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/modern-distributism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 14:56:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/modern-distributism/</guid>
      <description>Within the spectrum of philosophical positions, distributism presents itself as an incredibly valuable economic theory - one in which both the fundamental value and rights of individual humans are focused on as primary tenets. It is this focus, an elevation of the individual among the many, that puts it in direct contrast with the more commonly argued capitalism and socialism.
Capitalism maintains free markets and privately-held productive resources while socialism holds resources centrally via the state and regulates market systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Economics and Open Source</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/future-economics-and-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 18:38:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/future-economics-and-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Classic economics are primarily concerned with the balance of supply and demand in the marketplace. Balancing these two factors form the basis for current market operations based on individuals making production and consumption decisions in an open exchange. This open market supply-demand law is taken as one of two assumptions in this post&amp;rsquo;s thought experiment.
The second assumption is that our workforce is becoming increasingly automated; direct human involvement is gradually being replaced by automated tools and processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/open-source-hypothesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 20:42:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/posts/open-source-hypothesis/</guid>
      <description>Open source software has had a broadly positive impact on society.
Its resources have provided the basis for massive value creation and played key roles as the fundamental building blocks of technological innovation. There are dozens of available examples and it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary to address them in this piece. Needless to say, open source has left a lasting mark on the world.
But there may be potential for it to do even more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 17:02:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/books/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of science fiction short works. Currently, it is in a trilogy form but is under a continual &amp;ldquo;work-in-progress&amp;rdquo;; a large-scale revamp will likely be gradually implemented and steady edits should be expected for the corpus as a whole. Changes can be observed in the Git history.
 Knowing And Triumphant The Summation War Chosen For Elysium  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philly</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/philly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 14:46:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/philly/</guid>
      <description>via GIPHY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 14:44:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>John is a software engineer at HeavyWater and a part-time software engineer at CRFT. Additionally, he is an open source maker working to build resources to advance open source adoption and distributism.
He is a blogger and author and in his spare time, John enjoys lifting, yoga, and reading.
John resides in Philadelphia, PA and can be reached via direct message on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>