<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 08:39:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressive vs Expansive</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/progressive-vs-expansive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 08:39:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/progressive-vs-expansive/</guid>
      <description>The term &amp;ldquo;progressive&amp;rdquo; has been conflated with the word &amp;ldquo;expansive&amp;rdquo; with regards to legislative initiatives. In some ways, this is similar to the theme in Peter Thiel&amp;rsquo;s [1] book Zero to One [2].
 moving 0 -&amp;gt; 1 creates an entirely new solution moving 1 -&amp;gt; N scales an existing solution  The latter is dominant while being billed as the former in legislation. Currently, this is particularly true in two areas: minimum wage and college education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marian-Dedicated Work</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/marian-dedicated-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/marian-dedicated-work/</guid>
      <description>More of our common, day-to-day work must be dedicated to the Most Holy Mother of God [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Objectives</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/numerical-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/numerical-objectives/</guid>
      <description>Using numbers when defining a task establishes a specific and measureable outcome.
Even if the number is an estimate and the estimate is off, it is something that can be learned from and adjusted over time.
More importantly, the attached number helps mentally frame the task and make it mentally attainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Religion and Rocketry</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-religion-and-rocketry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 08:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-religion-and-rocketry/</guid>
      <description>The short essay &amp;ldquo;Religion and Rocketry&amp;rdquo; from C.S. Lewis&amp;rsquo; [1] collection The World&amp;rsquo;s Last Night [2] addresses the existence of extraterrestrial life.
What&amp;rsquo;s interesting about this piece is that it takes their existence for granted and digs into the theological and ethical implications their existence entails. Lewis poses a series of questions regarding their spiritual nature - two in particular ask whether the aliens are fallen, as we are, and what, if any, mechanism exists for their redemption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adversity Figures</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/adversity-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/adversity-figures/</guid>
      <description>Anecdotally to the observer, it seems that national adversity produces heroes while personal adversity produces victims.
 Why is there a perceived difference and why can&amp;rsquo;t personal adversity produce public heroes?
 In national-level issues, everyone is impacted and all shoulder the burden while a few rise as leaders. For example, in World War II individuals such as Churchill [1], Murphy [2], Winters [2], and Sendler [4] are rightfully treated as heroes for their noble defense of freedom even as the conflict touched all lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radical Rational</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/radical-rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/radical-rational/</guid>
      <description>Radically hold rational positions
 Being open to new ideas does not mean you need to immediately accept everything that comes your way. Challenge them, push them, fight them.
Let the best ideas win.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Orthodoxy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-orthodoxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-orthodoxy/</guid>
      <description>Here are a series of short notes on G.K. Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s [1] book Orthodoxy [2].
Chesterton earns the nickname the &amp;ldquo;prince of paradox&amp;rdquo;; every chapter contains multiple statements that flip the conventional perspective. Two statements in particular from the chapter &amp;ldquo;The Flag of the World&amp;rdquo; stood out.
 Rational optimism leads to stagnation; it is irrational optimism that leads to reform.
  The more transcendental is your patriotism, the more practical are your politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Impact</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/social-media-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/social-media-impact/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting series of questions that can be raised regarding social media listed below.
 Has the net impact of social media been positive or negative in developed nations? Has the net impact of social media been positive or negative in underdeveloped nations? If there is a difference in the answers to those questions, what causes the disparity?  These services have contributed positively and negatively to the world - identifying what distribution these contributions take would be valuable in helping to understand their proper function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Education</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/progressive-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/progressive-education/</guid>
      <description>A progressive approach to education is to experiment with new methods intead of focusing solely on expanding access to old methods.
These older methods, particularly the four year college in the U.S., are increasingly misaligned with student goals and fail to deliver successful outcomes. [1]
Pumping money into failing approaches is not progressive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amortal Death</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/amortal-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/amortal-death/</guid>
      <description>The moment we become amortal, God will have to kill us.
 The only thing that can kill an amortal being is an immortal one. And if our lives can&amp;rsquo;t end naturally, only the end of the universe will bring us down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Utah’s Economic Exceptionalism</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-utah-economic-exceptionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-utah-economic-exceptionalism/</guid>
      <description>Several aspects of the Beehive State&amp;rsquo;s socio-economic approach are discussed in an article titled &amp;ldquo;Utah’s Economic Exceptionalism&amp;rdquo; [1] by Natalie Gochnour.
While the state&amp;rsquo;s economic position was solid during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, both in terms of mitigating negative fallout and general rising economic performance, the basis for this success appears to have been in place well prior to the outbreak.
The article points to factors like low income disparity, high upward mobility, and even highly unusual feats such as under budget and early completion in major public works projects as indicators of the state&amp;rsquo;s favorable economic strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Capital Preference</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/social-capital-preference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/social-capital-preference/</guid>
      <description>Some companies rely heavily on social capital as part of their continued financial success. To varying degrees, this makes them dependent on current social trends.
However, even companies that are not overly impacted by social perception (e.g. ones with strong customer stickiness) seem to seek it out. In doing so they appear to voluntarily relinquish an advantageous position.
 Why take on an unnecessary dependency?
 Maybe there is or always has been a strong need to &amp;ldquo;belong&amp;rdquo; even in profit-driven enterprises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulated Majorities</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/encapsulated-majorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/encapsulated-majorities/</guid>
      <description>Increased local political autonomy may reduce voting majorities to their smallest sphere of influence. This would lead to many, independent, and encapsulated majorities operating within a larger, shared population.
Several interesting points arise in this situation:
 Any tyrannical majority is confined to a small operating area In worst cases even tyrannical majorities are likely generally aligned with local interests Constituents may easily move from tyrannical majorities to elsewhere within the larger population  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Bad Blood</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood/</guid>
      <description>This piece is on Bad Blood [1] by John Carreyrou [2].
I was familiar with the story of Elizabeth Holmes [3] and her company Theranos [4] but the book provided greater insight into how she interacted with people regarding her work.
It is unclear whether her extreme focus on &amp;ldquo;her mission&amp;rdquo; was a manipulative effort or actual self-denial; her actions could support both positions.
There are many instances of Holmes legally pursuing whistleblowers and publicly attacking external detractors - essentially anyone threatening the positive perception of Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Value Extraction</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/student-value-extraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/student-value-extraction/</guid>
      <description>As of the time of this writing, the average dropout rate for U.S. college freshmen is approximately 30%. Traditional four-year schools appear to be un/intentionally positioning for this to maximize value extraction from attending students.
Anecdotal observations point to freshman and sophomore classes having significantly higher student-teacher ratios than junior and senior classes, on average.
Several education spaces at the Penn State University Park campus have massive seating capacity and are often used by lower-year classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immediate Testing</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/immediate-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 10:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/immediate-testing/</guid>
      <description>Continuously testing entire code repositories increases the ability to introduce rapid changes. Being able to do this in early stages, such as the MVP, is highly valuable.
Simple approaches, like adding a unit_tests script to the repo containing just a go test ./... -coverage command [1][2] achieve this. Even though it would initially be triggered manually, doing so would provide value to the developer even before a complete CI/CD pipeline could be established.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Fratelli Tutti</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti/</guid>
      <description>This is a breakdown of the encyclical Fratelli Tutti [1] written by Pope Francis.
The encyclical covers a wide range of topics and displays a generally more political tone while attempting to balance diverging viewpoints. Sometimes this leads to over-simplification or self-contradiction.
This note primarily discusses socio-economic subjects and reference numbers are provided for the appropriate sections of the encyclical.
   Topic Summary Comments     Culture Exporting or copying cultural models reduces national identity (#51) and different cultures are not enemies (#147).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Action</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/silent-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/silent-action/</guid>
      <description>Actions taken to accomplish good works should be done without seeking attention.
 Sometimes attention is unavoidable but it should be reduced to the minimal amount needed to get the work done or to what will maximize the impact of the act.
Everything else above this minimized amount is performative and serves no other purpose than self-aggrandizement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noble Savage</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/noble-savage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/noble-savage/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes prior stages of human development are presented as a model to emulate with claims the early homo genuses better coexisted with their natural environment.
Contrary evidence [1] indicates early humans directly contributed to megafaunal extinction events across the globe; the correlative findings show mass extinctions were immediately preceeded by the arrival of migrating humans. Other factors may have contributed but these were not as significant as the presence of human hunters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Cynical Theories</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 08:45:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief summary of takeaways from reading Cynical Theories [1] by James Lindsay and Helen Pluckrose of &amp;ldquo;grievance studies affair&amp;rdquo; [2] infamy.
Overall, the book does an excellent job outlining the history of the overarching worldview termed &amp;ldquo;critical theory&amp;rdquo; as well as presenting a number of succinct counter arguments against it.
The most interesting topics covered are the breakdowns of the individual fields within the broader philosophy.
Tracing specific ancestries and outlining each field&amp;rsquo;s current form and emphasis within the umbrella is highly valuable; it highlights both specific facets that the laity may more successfully understand and grapple with as well as potentially destructive tensions between the fields making up &amp;ldquo;critical theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathe</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/breathe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/breathe/</guid>
      <description> Take a deep breath.
  And then take another.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservice News</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-news/</guid>
      <description>An alternative news consumption paradigm could be one where individuals build themselves ad-hoc collections to establish a &amp;ldquo;microservice architecture&amp;rdquo; of preferred sources. Ideally, these sources would be smaller groups or independent journalists potentially providing highly specialized coverage and reporting - some sources might even exist only as long as the story they cover. All news producers would be treated as modular and replaceable.
This fragmentation would force consumers to actively build their own networks while also reducing narrative centralization from large producers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friend Disagreements</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/friend-disagreements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 08:37:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/friend-disagreements/</guid>
      <description> Friends can disagree over things that matter.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressionism</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/impressionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/impressionism/</guid>
      <description>Impressionism [1] as a painting style has a strong personal, albeit uninformed, appeal.
The style prefers to see everything in a given scope without focusing on specific details. Produced images are more of a summary or a simplification of the subject which significantly reduces cognitive overhead in consuming these pieces.
A favorite is The Battle of the Kearsarge and the Alabama [2] by Édouard Manet, pictured below.
Personal highlights:
 smoke obscuring ship details or entire vessels quick lines for distant masts and rigging approximately two-thirds is water most of which is empty no specifics are conveyed on people in the image  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend Competition</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:40:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-competition/</guid>
      <description>A non-guaranteed citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend introduces fiscal competition between political parties that are members of the dividend issuing government.
For common equity dividends the amount per share is determined by profit surplus roughly calculated as revenue minus cost. Similarly, a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend is determined by government revenue minus government cost. Given government revenue is often primarily driven by taxation, the least impactful way to increase distributions to constituents is to reduce government costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Wozniak</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/anti-wozniak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 09:37:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/anti-wozniak/</guid>
      <description>Rapid development iteration following patterns like Agile [1] generates immediate product feedback which may be an antidote against not posessing raw talent displayed by people like Steve Wozniak [2].
Avoiding &amp;ldquo;representing yourself&amp;rdquo; [3] in the product removes the need to build perfection on the first deployment and will still eventually lead to a fully realized end result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Brainstorm</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-brainstorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 08:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-brainstorm/</guid>
      <description>Below is a loose, unordered collection of &amp;ldquo;radical&amp;rdquo;, but practically implementable, ideas for the U.S. political system. These have not been evaluated for completeness - this is a braindump. However, they may be expanded on individually in the future.
Ideas
 Comprehensive Federal term limits: all Federal-level roles, including the Vice Presidency, the Senate, the House, and the Supreme Court, would be term-limited. Service could be potentially capped at eight years each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend vs UBI</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 08:15:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi/</guid>
      <description>The difference in the concepts of a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend and universal basic income (&amp;ldquo;UBI&amp;rdquo;) are laid out in the terms &amp;ldquo;dividend&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;income.&amp;rdquo;
   Feature Dividend Income     Amount Floating value based on excess revenue Fixed value determined by contract   Frequency Non-guaranteed, likely monthly/quarterly Guaranteed, determined by contract   Source Equity ownership allocates share Labor contributed under contract    These features are present in fiscal policy options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splitting Education</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/splitting-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 08:06:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/splitting-education/</guid>
      <description>Currently, there is a conflation between higher education and vocational training. Typical, four-year degrees are providing both a general education and serving as credentialing frequently required in the workforce. Separating these aspects could provide more tailored services to students based on interest and need.
Educational
 &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; four-year college environment providing broad teachings and exposure to abstract concepts examples: history, higher-order math, music, computer theory, etc.   &amp;gt; more theoretical, less appied</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Duopoloy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-duopoloy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 08:32:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-duopoloy/</guid>
      <description>Established political duopolies hold their members on platforms that can devolve into what can be summarized as &amp;ldquo;anti-opposing party.&amp;rdquo; Time is spent condemning the opposition&amp;rsquo;s stances without defending, or sometimes even presenting, alternatives. While there may be philosophic stratification within the dual parties, these differences are subordinate to the party positions.
Splitting these duopolies into multiple mini-parties encourages more active discourse and requires proactive engagement among colleagues when presenting and defending positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgism and Energy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/georgism-and-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 08:20:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/georgism-and-energy/</guid>
      <description>The land value tax (&amp;ldquo;LVT&amp;rdquo;) at the center of Georgism directly encourages efficient land usage in energy production. Given that this core principal assesses taxes as a percentage of the value of the land held, it drives producers to establish the smallest physical footprint possible.
If it were introduced, there would be an immediate impact to all existing energy producers:
 &amp;ldquo;Traditional&amp;rdquo; fuels (e.g. oil, LNG, coal): large land, and potentially offshore, resources would be adjusted to find the optimal boundary of exerting exclusive rights to the resources and minimizing the taxable land held; additionally the valuable resources held in the land would increase the land value and taxes owed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharmaceuticals As Software</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/pharma-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 08:25:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/pharma-software/</guid>
      <description>Some characteristics of pharmaceuticals make them comparable to software. Basically software and pharmaceuticals have:
 high development costs low distribution costs  For example, both require a large, upfront resource investment in research and composition. After initial R&amp;amp;D expenses, both are relatively easily manufactured and distributed at scale.
Knowing this, pharmaceuticals may be well placed to leverage wide-reaching treatments while reducing healthcare costs. Additionally, with precision medicine [1], highly-focused solutions can be developed or even compounded on-demand for individual use to increase effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Team Skill</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/small-team-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:20:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/small-team-skill/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important skills a small team can collectively have is the ability to identify what they don&amp;rsquo;t need to build for a minimum viable product (&amp;ldquo;MVP&amp;rdquo;).
Smaller teams inherently have fewer human resources available to build things and must prioritize. An open two-way dialogue between the team and the customer helps identify the core value the product provides the customers. With this the team can provide that initial core value in their MVP even if it&amp;rsquo;s held together with rubber bands and bubble gum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Born With Nothing</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/born-with-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 08:24:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/born-with-nothing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s worth reiterating that you are born with nothing and no one owes you anything. All you have are your rights and even those have been endowed to you.
 Remember you are dust and unto dust you shall return.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Authority Skeptic</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 08:33:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic/</guid>
      <description>Being a healthy skeptic of authority is a good thing. The keyword being healthy.
A certain amount of structure is definitely necessary to enable human socio-economic interactions. But evaluations of the structure should be constantly made:
 Evaluate the validity of the those in authority - does their position of power stem from the governed? Evaluate whether their actions fall within the purview of those in authority - are they doing what they have the capacity to do on behalf of the governed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Laws</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:39:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws/</guid>
      <description>Laws can and should be based on immutable, moral principles, but that does not mean we need to codify and enforce every one of our morals on other people.
Sins should be easier to commit than laws should be to break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Decisions</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 08:41:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-decisions/</guid>
      <description>The individuals best suited for making decisions on any solution are those closest to the problem. It is the leader&amp;rsquo;s only job to facilitate these decisions. A leader should:
 Provide guidance when it is requested Arbitrate disputes when they arise Make decisions when presented options Spread vision and purpose when leading  Leaders should work to empower individuals to make their own decisions and only impose their own when absolutely necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging Work</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 08:47:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-work/</guid>
      <description>People don&amp;rsquo;t just seek out employment - they seek out work and a meaningful way to contribute to and participate in the world around them.
It&amp;rsquo;s good to challenge yourself through your professional endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness vs Joy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/happiness-vs-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 08:49:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/happiness-vs-joy/</guid>
      <description>There is a difference between happiness and joy.
Happiness is the emotion. Joy is the spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Mesas</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/economic-mesas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 08:54:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/economic-mesas/</guid>
      <description>A citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend would create an &amp;ldquo;economic mesa&amp;rdquo; and establish a natural and humane border.
Following the Georgist [1] model, a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend would have the side effect of providing an additional method for defining and enforcing sovereign territory. Legal citizens would receive the non-guaranteed dividend, pro rata, which would generally shift prices higher in the region they spend it - predominantly where they live. A resource disparity would arise between the citizens and the citizens of neighboring countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Equity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reverse-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 08:58:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reverse-equity/</guid>
      <description>Something to consider:
 Equity creates equity in the employees from the point of view of the company.
  Equity: relatively non-liquid asset conveying financial value from dividends and non-financial value from voting rights Salary: highly liquid asset conveying financial value on receipt and provides no non-financial value  The former establishes a direct and more-or-less permanent investment in the company by the employee while the latter is available to the employee only through the life of the employment contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophic Ancestry</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/philosophic-ancestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:20:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/philosophic-ancestry/</guid>
      <description>While I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with most philosophic and religious traditions, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine a world that is better where Great Meteoron, Potala Palace, Shaolin Temple, Simonopetra, Blagaj Tekke, Sera Monastery, Tungnath, and many others, are silent. I really believe these monuments, and the faiths that they symbolize, to be important to our shared social fabric and our connection to our past.
The beauty and diversity of antique philosophy should be fought for and maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities For Good</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/opportunities-for-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 12:24:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/opportunities-for-good/</guid>
      <description>Something that strikes me:
 Small opportunities to be good seem so difficult to take advantage of while the truly great require no deliberation.
 I wonder if this has to do with smaller opportunities so often coming into conflict with prevailing social norms while the options that accompany truly great opportunities are universally held to be true. Now this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say the small are lesser but that accomplishing them requires a different kind of courage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boring Problems</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/boring-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 13:36:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/boring-problems/</guid>
      <description>Boring problems often have fascinating solutions.
 This may be more or less true, and is likely dependent on personal experience, but I’ve found that boring problems have typically been left un-explored for the very reason that they’re boring. This makes it all new territory for someone venturing into it. Whatever they make to solve the problem will be entirely new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation Percentages</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/conversation-percentages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 13:38:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/conversation-percentages/</guid>
      <description>So many people forget that fifty percent of every conversation between two people is silence.
Active listening is a real thing; when I realize someone is really listening, the conversation has real meaning. I strive to provide the same attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Sip</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/first-sip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 13:40:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/first-sip/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re kicking back in the evening&amp;hellip;
 Enjoy the first sip of your beer.
 Especially when you&amp;rsquo;ve held off drinking all week and Friday rolls around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War King</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/war-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:45:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/war-king/</guid>
      <description>The king who avoids war at all costs is the king to avoid in war.
 Those who are passionate for peace will passionately pursue its return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Conversation</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 18:23:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes facilitating conversation is more important than contributing to it.
Try working with developers talking past each other for thirty minutes and you&amp;rsquo;ll see how this makes sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Project Principles</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/core-project-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 18:29:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/core-project-principles/</guid>
      <description>Collaboration, communication, community.
 These are three core principles I look for in projects I associate myself with. Open/active discussions about the roadmap with no one individual deciding things, clearly and consistently adhering to a roadmap, and including all stakeholders in formalizing the roadmap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements Over Process</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/requirements-over-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 18:31:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/requirements-over-process/</guid>
      <description>Favor requirements over processes while building. When you do need a process, automate it.
By this I mean prioritize quality or production requirements rather than dictating how to build things. Creating process pipelines, or enforcing strict architectures before they can be evaluated, likely stifles creativity - anything needing a process should be automated and never thought about.
Basically: let people be creative and then when they&amp;rsquo;ve built some cool things, formalize and automate the things that prevent them from being creative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Resource Creativity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/minimal-resource-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 19:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/minimal-resource-creativity/</guid>
      <description>It really seems like a minimal resource set necessitates creative solutions and efficient design.
I’m a firm believer in this. It’s sort of like building with a limited number of LEGOs: it forces you to think creatively and with imagination while also knowing intimately the number of pieces you have left and how they can work together.
 Necessity is the mother of invention.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Solution Fun</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-solution-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 19:25:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-solution-fun/</guid>
      <description>Building simple solutions is fun.
This falls in with my overall philosophy of minimalism. Build lots of simple solutions and then weave them together to form something big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Variables</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:28:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables/</guid>
      <description>Variables utilized in human decision making should be based in the natural world rather than arbitrary selection.
An example of this is consent. In order for consent to be actually given, the individual has to be fully cognizant of the situation and not coerced. Being cognizant would, theoretically, require a fully developed brain - although this can’t be accurately assessed on-demand and on a case-by-case basis, the age for consent (alcohol, military service, driving, sex, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Burnout</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/work-burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:40:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/work-burnout/</guid>
      <description>Work is still work - it isn&amp;rsquo;t always fun. But it sucks when it used to be.
It&amp;rsquo;s a bit whiny but feeling burnout at work, especially when the environment used to be engaging, fun, dynamic, and rewarding, really sucks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increased Self-Direction</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/increased-self-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 19:44:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/increased-self-direction/</guid>
      <description>The goal of increased individual self-direction requires providing both the individual decision-making capacity and the resources to take action with.
This is a personal goal of mine to provide both of these factors for both myself in my own life and for others in theirs. Individuals should be maximally free to self-direct and be able to utilize as many resources as possible, in many cases, to engage in productive endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging Innovations</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-innovations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 19:48:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-innovations/</guid>
      <description>Many innovations today focus on making life easier - why not build things that make life more challenging?
This sounds silly but I like the idea of building things that push us forward and challenge us physically, mentally, emotionally, spiritually, philosophically. Things like hard science and deep tech are going to really push us more than service-based innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweat Equity Unification</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/sweat-equity-unification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 19:50:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/sweat-equity-unification/</guid>
      <description>Companies that unite shareholders and stakeholders invest in their employees and community. And this happens at the same time.
Introducing perpetually issued and held &amp;ldquo;sweat equity&amp;rdquo; for employees helps to build bonds with employees and alleviate reliance on the &amp;ldquo;salary drug.&amp;rdquo; Bringing these two together lets individuals keep what they build. [1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservice Economy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 19:54:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-economy/</guid>
      <description>Large numbers of small producers reduces market consolidation and increases economic resiliency. Sort of an microserivce economy.
While there&amp;rsquo;s nothing inherently wrong with large producers, who often provide beneficial economies of scale, smaller operations may more easily avoid turning employees into &amp;ldquo;cogs.&amp;rdquo; Also, with smaller operations, there&amp;rsquo;s less possibility of drastic market centralization and consolidation of risk. No one entity dictates the activities of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craftsmanship Pride</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/craftsmanship-pride/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 19:57:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/craftsmanship-pride/</guid>
      <description>An important aspect of craftsmanship is earning the pride you take in your work.
The &amp;ldquo;niche&amp;rdquo; production approach where output is owned by the individuals who produce it, as encouraged by distributism, encourages thoughtful satisfaction in one&amp;rsquo;s accomplishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributism Maker Ownership</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/distributism-maker-ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 19:59:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/distributism-maker-ownership/</guid>
      <description>The theory of distributism [1] encourages maker ownership of the means and output of production while maintaining a free market. Together, this makes for a system designed around individual self-direction and establishes human dignity at the center of the philosophy.
A move towards distributism is a move towards a true system of social justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statues</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/statues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 20:09:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/statues/</guid>
      <description>Don’t build statues to people who are still alive.
 Best practice to avoid making people into gods in their own minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Truths</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 08:53:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-truths/</guid>
      <description>The greatest truths are simple. Probably one of the most important things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from C.S. Lewis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where You&#39;re From</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/where-youre-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 08:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/where-youre-from/</guid>
      <description>Where you&amp;rsquo;re from is only important if you&amp;rsquo;ve never left - otherwise, what matters is where you&amp;rsquo;re going.
Maybe a tad cliche, but whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable Dignity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/vulnerable-dignity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 08:56:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/vulnerable-dignity/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in a loss in dignity simply because one is vulnerable. There is no shame in asking for help. There is only shame in demanding it or denying it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friends Favors</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/friends-favors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 09:00:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/friends-favors/</guid>
      <description>Friends don&amp;rsquo;t perform favors for friends, they just help their friends when they need it.
Sort of a cheesy thing to say, but I believe it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Blood</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/family-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 09:01:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/family-blood/</guid>
      <description>Family is more than blood.
 While I think blood is a decent, in most cases, default binding connection, I believe we can hold those that we choose to associate ourselves with in similarly high regard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unscripted Interactions</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/unscripted-interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 09:04:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/unscripted-interactions/</guid>
      <description>Unscripted interactions are the truest demonstration of a subject matter knowledge and interest.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always preferred unscripted and unprompted discussions. I think the reason for this is because I think it shows a more genuine side of the subject.
For example, I prefer the live/unscripted entertainment bits provided by Rooster Teeth and Funhaus over the more choreographed pieces. Similarly, I think I received more thoughtful and groundbreaking insight from C.S. Lewis&amp;rsquo;s notes and letter than I have from most of his &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Productivity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 18:57:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing productive output while maintaining individual rights and dignity is the primary concern in an increasingly automated workforce system. Open source caters to this scenario and provides hyper-productive individuals with a series of resources to leverage their output and effectively provide for consumers.
Benefits
 Common knowledge pool: shared and open intellectual property which reduces &amp;ldquo;reinvention&amp;rdquo; by participants creating proprietary alternatives Non-overlapping markets: entities focus on &amp;ldquo;peripheral&amp;rdquo; markets surrounding shared core resources which encourages focus on competitive advantages Lower entry barriers: new participants can enter market rapidly as core intellectual property is openly available for use Value creation prioritization: more value is created from open resources than is captured by each individual producer Balances market forces: monopolization and perfect competition are avoided through public core resources and competitive advantage focuses Supply chain cooperation: &amp;ldquo;niche&amp;rdquo; edge producers collaborating between individual horizontal and vertical segments Adaptive technologies: common core resources with multiple contributors provides rapid updates for changing environments/requirements  Consumers benefit in this scenario of a hyper-productive minority operating in a highly automated workforce through more rapid innovation and product development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Competition</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:19:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition/</guid>
      <description>The state is a monopoly on legislation; democracy is out best way of introducing competition.
I generally stand against any kind of monopoly and I think, in some respects, the state can be described in this way. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it abolished, but I do want it challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Economic Good</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:29:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good/</guid>
      <description>Open source software projects are a collaborative effort. Individual developers contribute to the betterment of the project and create a publicly available, shared resource.
This model opts to create, rather than directly capture, value. Additionally, competitive markets are maintained around the project since individuals are free to take it and build products or services using it.
Since all parties share core intellectual property, competition is encouraged around the &amp;ldquo;edges&amp;rdquo; and where comparative advantages apply with some participants opting to keep these facets closed source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Others</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/working-with-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 19:31:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/working-with-others/</guid>
      <description>Provide alternatives, don&amp;rsquo;t poke holes.
Fight for the best idea, not yours.
Think flexibly.
 Just some small one-liners that I think are valuable for me to keep in mind when working with others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>