<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Value Extraction</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/student-value-extraction-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/student-value-extraction-1-0/</guid>
      <description>As of the time of this writing, the average dropout rate for U.S. college freshmen is approximately 30%. Traditional four-year schools appear to be un/intentionally positioning for this to maximize value extraction from attending students.
Anecdotal observations point to freshman and sophomore classes having significantly higher student-teacher ratios than junior and senior classes, on average.
Several education spaces at the Penn State University Park campus have massive seating capacity and are often used by lower-year classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splitting Education</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/splitting-education-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 08:06:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/splitting-education-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Currently, there is a conflation between higher education and vocational training. Typical, four-year degrees are providing both a general education and serving as credentialing frequently required in the workforce. Separating these aspects could provide more tailored services to students based on interest and need.
Educational
 &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; four-year college environment providing broad teachings and exposure to abstract concepts examples: history, higher-order math, music, computer theory, etc.   &amp;gt; more theoretical, less appied</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>