<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>economics on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in economics on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 08:54:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Mesas</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/economic-mesas-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 08:54:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/economic-mesas-1-0/</guid>
      <description>A citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend would create an &amp;ldquo;economic mesa&amp;rdquo; and establish a natural and humane border.
Following the Georgist [1] model, a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend would have the side effect of providing an additional method for defining and enforcing sovereign territory. Legal citizens would receive the non-guaranteed dividend, pro rata, which would generally shift prices higher in the region they spend it - predominantly where they live. A resource disparity would arise between the citizens and the citizens of neighboring countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Equity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reverse-equity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 08:58:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reverse-equity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Something to consider:
 Equity creates equity in the employees from the point of view of the company.
  Equity: relatively non-liquid asset conveying financial value from dividends and non-financial value from voting rights Salary: highly liquid asset conveying financial value on receipt and provides no non-financial value  The former establishes a direct and more-or-less permanent investment in the company by the employee while the latter is available to the employee only through the life of the employment contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweat Equity Unification</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/sweat-equity-unification-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 19:50:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/sweat-equity-unification-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Companies that unite shareholders and stakeholders invest in their employees and community. And this happens at the same time.
Introducing perpetually issued and held &amp;ldquo;sweat equity&amp;rdquo; for employees helps to build bonds with employees and alleviate reliance on the &amp;ldquo;salary drug.&amp;rdquo; Bringing these two together lets individuals keep what they build. [1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservice Economy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-economy-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 19:54:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-economy-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Large numbers of small producers reduces market consolidation and increases economic resiliency. Sort of an microserivce economy.
While there&amp;rsquo;s nothing inherently wrong with large producers, who often provide beneficial economies of scale, smaller operations may more easily avoid turning employees into &amp;ldquo;cogs.&amp;rdquo; Also, with smaller operations, there&amp;rsquo;s less possibility of drastic market centralization and consolidation of risk. No one entity dictates the activities of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craftsmanship Pride</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/craftsmanship-pride-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 19:57:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/craftsmanship-pride-1-0/</guid>
      <description>An important aspect of craftsmanship is earning the pride you take in your work.
The &amp;ldquo;niche&amp;rdquo; production approach where output is owned by the individuals who produce it, as encouraged by distributism, encourages thoughtful satisfaction in one&amp;rsquo;s accomplishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributism Maker Ownership</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/distributism-maker-ownership-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 19:59:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/distributism-maker-ownership-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The theory of distributism [1] encourages maker ownership of the means and output of production while maintaining a free market. Together, this makes for a system designed around individual self-direction and establishes human dignity at the center of the philosophy.
A move towards distributism is a move towards a true system of social justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Productivity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 18:57:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing productive output while maintaining individual rights and dignity is the primary concern in an increasingly automated workforce system. Open source caters to this scenario and provides hyper-productive individuals with a series of resources to leverage their output and effectively provide for consumers.
Benefits
 Common knowledge pool: shared and open intellectual property which reduces &amp;ldquo;reinvention&amp;rdquo; by participants creating proprietary alternatives Non-overlapping markets: entities focus on &amp;ldquo;peripheral&amp;rdquo; markets surrounding shared core resources which encourages focus on competitive advantages Lower entry barriers: new participants can enter market rapidly as core intellectual property is openly available for use Value creation prioritization: more value is created from open resources than is captured by each individual producer Balances market forces: monopolization and perfect competition are avoided through public core resources and competitive advantage focuses Supply chain cooperation: &amp;ldquo;niche&amp;rdquo; edge producers collaborating between individual horizontal and vertical segments Adaptive technologies: common core resources with multiple contributors provides rapid updates for changing environments/requirements  Consumers benefit in this scenario of a hyper-productive minority operating in a highly automated workforce through more rapid innovation and product development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Economic Good</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:29:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Open source software projects are a collaborative effort. Individual developers contribute to the betterment of the project and create a publicly available, shared resource.
This model opts to create, rather than directly capture, value. Additionally, competitive markets are maintained around the project since individuals are free to take it and build products or services using it.
Since all parties share core intellectual property, competition is encouraged around the &amp;ldquo;edges&amp;rdquo; and where comparative advantages apply with some participants opting to keep these facets closed source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>