<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:20:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Team Skill</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/small-team-skill-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:20:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/small-team-skill-1-0/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important skills a small team can collectively have is the ability to identify what they don&amp;rsquo;t need to build for a minimum viable product (&amp;ldquo;MVP&amp;rdquo;).
Smaller teams inherently have fewer human resources available to build things and must prioritize. An open two-way dialogue between the team and the customer helps identify the core value the product provides the customers. With this the team can provide that initial core value in their MVP even if it&amp;rsquo;s held together with rubber bands and bubble gum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Decisions</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-decisions-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 08:41:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-decisions-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The individuals best suited for making decisions on any solution are those closest to the problem. It is the leader&amp;rsquo;s only job to facilitate these decisions. A leader should:
 Provide guidance when it is requested Arbitrate disputes when they arise Make decisions when presented options Spread vision and purpose when leading  Leaders should work to empower individuals to make their own decisions and only impose their own when absolutely necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging Work</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-work-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 08:47:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-work-1-0/</guid>
      <description>People don&amp;rsquo;t just seek out employment - they seek out work and a meaningful way to contribute to and participate in the world around them.
It&amp;rsquo;s good to challenge yourself through your professional endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Equity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reverse-equity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 08:58:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reverse-equity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Something to consider:
 Equity creates equity in the employees from the point of view of the company.
  Equity: relatively non-liquid asset conveying financial value from dividends and non-financial value from voting rights Salary: highly liquid asset conveying financial value on receipt and provides no non-financial value  The former establishes a direct and more-or-less permanent investment in the company by the employee while the latter is available to the employee only through the life of the employment contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Conversation</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-conversation-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 18:23:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/facilitating-conversation-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes facilitating conversation is more important than contributing to it.
Try working with developers talking past each other for thirty minutes and you&amp;rsquo;ll see how this makes sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Project Principles</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/core-project-principles-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 18:29:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/core-project-principles-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Collaboration, communication, community.
 These are three core principles I look for in projects I associate myself with. Open/active discussions about the roadmap with no one individual deciding things, clearly and consistently adhering to a roadmap, and including all stakeholders in formalizing the roadmap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements Over Process</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/requirements-over-process-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 18:31:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/requirements-over-process-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Favor requirements over processes while building. When you do need a process, automate it.
By this I mean prioritize quality or production requirements rather than dictating how to build things. Creating process pipelines, or enforcing strict architectures before they can be evaluated, likely stifles creativity - anything needing a process should be automated and never thought about.
Basically: let people be creative and then when they&amp;rsquo;ve built some cool things, formalize and automate the things that prevent them from being creative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Resource Creativity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/minimal-resource-creativity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 19:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/minimal-resource-creativity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>It really seems like a minimal resource set necessitates creative solutions and efficient design.
I’m a firm believer in this. It’s sort of like building with a limited number of LEGOs: it forces you to think creatively and with imagination while also knowing intimately the number of pieces you have left and how they can work together.
 Necessity is the mother of invention.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Burnout</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/work-burnout-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:40:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/work-burnout-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Work is still work - it isn&amp;rsquo;t always fun. But it sucks when it used to be.
It&amp;rsquo;s a bit whiny but feeling burnout at work, especially when the environment used to be engaging, fun, dynamic, and rewarding, really sucks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increased Self-Direction</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/increased-self-direction-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 19:44:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/increased-self-direction-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The goal of increased individual self-direction requires providing both the individual decision-making capacity and the resources to take action with.
This is a personal goal of mine to provide both of these factors for both myself in my own life and for others in theirs. Individuals should be maximally free to self-direct and be able to utilize as many resources as possible, in many cases, to engage in productive endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging Innovations</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-innovations-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 19:48:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-innovations-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Many innovations today focus on making life easier - why not build things that make life more challenging?
This sounds silly but I like the idea of building things that push us forward and challenge us physically, mentally, emotionally, spiritually, philosophically. Things like hard science and deep tech are going to really push us more than service-based innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweat Equity Unification</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/sweat-equity-unification-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 19:50:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/sweat-equity-unification-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Companies that unite shareholders and stakeholders invest in their employees and community. And this happens at the same time.
Introducing perpetually issued and held &amp;ldquo;sweat equity&amp;rdquo; for employees helps to build bonds with employees and alleviate reliance on the &amp;ldquo;salary drug.&amp;rdquo; Bringing these two together lets individuals keep what they build. [1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Others</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/working-with-others-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 19:31:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/working-with-others-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Provide alternatives, don&amp;rsquo;t poke holes.
Fight for the best idea, not yours.
Think flexibly.
 Just some small one-liners that I think are valuable for me to keep in mind when working with others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>