<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 08:15:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: The Second World Wars</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-the-second-world-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 08:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-the-second-world-wars/</guid>
      <description>There are several interesting takeaways from Victor Davis Hanson&amp;rsquo;s The Second World Wars [1]. The whole work is presented from a numerical viewpoint and basically offers &amp;ldquo;accountant&amp;rsquo;s lessons&amp;rdquo; from the war. Here are some that stood out to me.
 Emphasize support resources
  Massive production of basic support vehicles and robust supply lines were a constant focus for the Allies throughout the war &amp;ldquo;Boring&amp;rdquo; things like unarmed and unarmored trucks were essential in ensuring sustainable campaigning   Produce fewer similar models</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: The Coddling of the American Mind</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief summary of The Coddling of the American Mind [1] by Greg Lukianoff and Jonathan Haidt.
In short, it is a well developed, explained, and supported book that is heavily data-driven. Overall, the book is critical of the &amp;ldquo;safetyism&amp;rdquo; which is increasingly present in society and encourages building more resillient members of the broader community.
The authors highlight specific issues in how the younger generations (at the time of its writing) are being raised and present targeted solutions that parents may act upon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Religion and Rocketry</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-religion-and-rocketry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 08:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-religion-and-rocketry/</guid>
      <description>The short essay &amp;ldquo;Religion and Rocketry&amp;rdquo; from C.S. Lewis&amp;rsquo; [1] collection The World&amp;rsquo;s Last Night [2] addresses the existence of extraterrestrial life.
What&amp;rsquo;s interesting about this piece is that it takes their existence for granted and digs into the theological and ethical implications their existence entails. Lewis poses a series of questions regarding their spiritual nature - two in particular ask whether the aliens are fallen, as we are, and what, if any, mechanism exists for their redemption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Orthodoxy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-orthodoxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-orthodoxy/</guid>
      <description>Here are a series of short notes on G.K. Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s [1] book Orthodoxy [2].
Chesterton earns the nickname the &amp;ldquo;prince of paradox&amp;rdquo;; every chapter contains multiple statements that flip the conventional perspective. Two statements in particular from the chapter &amp;ldquo;The Flag of the World&amp;rdquo; stood out.
 Rational optimism leads to stagnation; it is irrational optimism that leads to reform.
  The more transcendental is your patriotism, the more practical are your politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Utah’s Economic Exceptionalism</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-utah-economic-exceptionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-utah-economic-exceptionalism/</guid>
      <description>Several aspects of the Beehive State&amp;rsquo;s socio-economic approach are discussed in an article titled &amp;ldquo;Utah’s Economic Exceptionalism&amp;rdquo; [1] by Natalie Gochnour.
While the state&amp;rsquo;s economic position was solid during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, both in terms of mitigating negative fallout and general rising economic performance, the basis for this success appears to have been in place well prior to the outbreak.
The article points to factors like low income disparity, high upward mobility, and even highly unusual feats such as under budget and early completion in major public works projects as indicators of the state&amp;rsquo;s favorable economic strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Bad Blood</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood/</guid>
      <description>This piece is on Bad Blood [1] by John Carreyrou [2].
I was familiar with the story of Elizabeth Holmes [3] and her company Theranos [4] but the book provided greater insight into how she interacted with people regarding her work.
It is unclear whether her extreme focus on &amp;ldquo;her mission&amp;rdquo; was a manipulative effort or actual self-denial; her actions could support both positions.
There are many instances of Holmes legally pursuing whistleblowers and publicly attacking external detractors - essentially anyone threatening the positive perception of Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Fratelli Tutti</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti/</guid>
      <description>This is a breakdown of the encyclical Fratelli Tutti [1] written by Pope Francis.
The encyclical covers a wide range of topics and displays a generally more political tone while attempting to balance diverging viewpoints. Sometimes this leads to over-simplification or self-contradiction.
This note primarily discusses socio-economic subjects and reference numbers are provided for the appropriate sections of the encyclical.
   Topic Summary Comments     Culture Exporting or copying cultural models reduces national identity (#51) and different cultures are not enemies (#147).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Cynical Theories</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 08:45:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief summary of takeaways from reading Cynical Theories [1] by James Lindsay and Helen Pluckrose of &amp;ldquo;grievance studies affair&amp;rdquo; [2] infamy.
Overall, the book does an excellent job outlining the history of the overarching worldview termed &amp;ldquo;critical theory&amp;rdquo; as well as presenting a number of succinct counter arguments against it.
The most interesting topics covered are the breakdowns of the individual fields within the broader philosophy.
Tracing specific ancestries and outlining each field&amp;rsquo;s current form and emphasis within the umbrella is highly valuable; it highlights both specific facets that the laity may more successfully understand and grapple with as well as potentially destructive tensions between the fields making up &amp;ldquo;critical theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>