<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Utah’s Economic Exceptionalism</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-utah-economic-exceptionalism-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-utah-economic-exceptionalism-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Several aspects of the Beehive State&amp;rsquo;s socio-economic approach are discussed in an article titled &amp;ldquo;Utah’s Economic Exceptionalism&amp;rdquo; [1] by Natalie Gochnour.
While the state&amp;rsquo;s economic position was solid during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, both in terms of mitigating negative fallout and general rising economic performance, the basis for this success appears to have been in place well prior to the outbreak.
The article points to factors like low income disparity, high upward mobility, and even highly unusual feats such as under budget and early completion in major public works projects as indicators of the state&amp;rsquo;s favorable economic strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Bad Blood</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood-1-0/</guid>
      <description>This piece is on Bad Blood [1] by John Carreyrou [2].
I was familiar with the story of Elizabeth Holmes [3] and her company Theranos [4] but the book provided greater insight into how she interacted with people regarding her work.
It is unclear whether her extreme focus on &amp;ldquo;her mission&amp;rdquo; was a manipulative effort or actual self-denial; her actions could support both positions.
There are many instances of Holmes legally pursuing whistleblowers and publicly attacking external detractors - essentially anyone threatening the positive perception of Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Fratelli Tutti</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti-1-0/</guid>
      <description>This is a breakdown of the encyclical Fratelli Tutti [1] written by Pope Francis.
The encyclical covers a wide range of topics and displays a generally more political tone while attempting to balance diverging viewpoints. Sometimes this leads to over-simplification or self-contradiction.
This note primarily discusses socio-economic subjects and reference numbers are provided for the appropriate sections of the encyclical.
   Topic Summary Comments     Culture Exporting or copying cultural models reduces national identity (#51) and different cultures are not enemies (#147).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Cynical Theories</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 08:45:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories-1-0/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief summary of takeaways from reading Cynical Theories [1] by James Lindsay and Helen Pluckrose of &amp;ldquo;grievance studies affair&amp;rdquo; [2] infamy.
Overall, the book does an excellent job outlining the history of the overarching worldview termed &amp;ldquo;critical theory&amp;rdquo; as well as presenting a number of succinct counter arguments against it.
The most interesting topics covered are the breakdowns of the individual fields within the broader philosophy.
Tracing specific ancestries and outlining each field&amp;rsquo;s current form and emphasis within the umbrella is highly valuable; it highlights both specific facets that the laity may more successfully understand and grapple with as well as potentially destructive tensions between the fields making up &amp;ldquo;critical theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>