<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/social/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microservice News</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-news-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-news-1-0/</guid>
      <description>An alternative news consumption paradigm could be one where individuals build themselves ad-hoc collections to establish a &amp;ldquo;microservice architecture&amp;rdquo; of preferred sources. Ideally, these sources would be smaller groups or independent journalists potentially providing highly specialized coverage and reporting - some sources might even exist only as long as the story they cover. All news producers would be treated as modular and replaceable.
This fragmentation would force consumers to actively build their own networks while also reducing narrative centralization from large producers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend Competition</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-competition-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:40:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-competition-1-0/</guid>
      <description>A non-guaranteed citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend introduces fiscal competition between political parties that are members of the dividend issuing government.
For common equity dividends the amount per share is determined by profit surplus roughly calculated as revenue minus cost. Similarly, a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend is determined by government revenue minus government cost. Given government revenue is often primarily driven by taxation, the least impactful way to increase distributions to constituents is to reduce government costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend vs UBI</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 08:15:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The difference in the concepts of a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend and universal basic income (&amp;ldquo;UBI&amp;rdquo;) are laid out in the terms &amp;ldquo;dividend&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;income.&amp;rdquo;
   Feature Dividend Income     Amount Floating value based on excess revenue Fixed value determined by contract   Frequency Non-guaranteed, likely monthly/quarterly Guaranteed, determined by contract   Source Equity ownership allocates share Labor contributed under contract    These features are present in fiscal policy options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgism and Energy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/georgism-and-energy-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 08:20:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/georgism-and-energy-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The land value tax (&amp;ldquo;LVT&amp;rdquo;) at the center of Georgism directly encourages efficient land usage in energy production. Given that this core principal assesses taxes as a percentage of the value of the land held, it drives producers to establish the smallest physical footprint possible.
If it were introduced, there would be an immediate impact to all existing energy producers:
 &amp;ldquo;Traditional&amp;rdquo; fuels (e.g. oil, LNG, coal): large land, and potentially offshore, resources would be adjusted to find the optimal boundary of exerting exclusive rights to the resources and minimizing the taxable land held; additionally the valuable resources held in the land would increase the land value and taxes owed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Authority Skeptic</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 08:33:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Being a healthy skeptic of authority is a good thing. The keyword being healthy.
A certain amount of structure is definitely necessary to enable human socio-economic interactions. But evaluations of the structure should be constantly made:
 Evaluate the validity of the those in authority - does their position of power stem from the governed? Evaluate whether their actions fall within the purview of those in authority - are they doing what they have the capacity to do on behalf of the governed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Laws</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:39:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Laws can and should be based on immutable, moral principles, but that does not mean we need to codify and enforce every one of our morals on other people.
Sins should be easier to commit than laws should be to break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophic Ancestry</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/philosophic-ancestry-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:20:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/philosophic-ancestry-1-0/</guid>
      <description>While I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with most philosophic and religious traditions, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine a world that is better where Great Meteoron, Potala Palace, Shaolin Temple, Simonopetra, Blagaj Tekke, Sera Monastery, Tungnath, and many others, are silent. I really believe these monuments, and the faiths that they symbolize, to be important to our shared social fabric and our connection to our past.
The beauty and diversity of antique philosophy should be fought for and maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities for Good</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/opportunities-for-good-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 12:24:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/opportunities-for-good-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Something that strikes me:
 Small opportunities to be good seem so difficult to take advantage of while the truly great require no deliberation.
 I wonder if this has to do with smaller opportunities so often coming into conflict with prevailing social norms while the options that accompany truly great opportunities are universally held to be true. Now this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say the small are lesser but that accomplishing them requires a different kind of courage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservice Economy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-economy-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 19:54:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/microservice-economy-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Large numbers of small producers reduces market consolidation and increases economic resiliency. Sort of an microserivce economy.
While there&amp;rsquo;s nothing inherently wrong with large producers, who often provide beneficial economies of scale, smaller operations may more easily avoid turning employees into &amp;ldquo;cogs.&amp;rdquo; Also, with smaller operations, there&amp;rsquo;s less possibility of drastic market centralization and consolidation of risk. No one entity dictates the activities of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributism Maker Ownership</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/distributism-maker-ownership-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 19:59:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/distributism-maker-ownership-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The theory of distributism [1] encourages maker ownership of the means and output of production while maintaining a free market. Together, this makes for a system designed around individual self-direction and establishes human dignity at the center of the philosophy.
A move towards distributism is a move towards a true system of social justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statues</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/statues-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 20:09:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/statues-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Don’t build statues to people who are still alive.
 Best practice to avoid making people into gods in their own minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable Dignity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/vulnerable-dignity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 08:56:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/vulnerable-dignity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in a loss in dignity simply because one is vulnerable. There is no shame in asking for help. There is only shame in demanding it or denying it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Productivity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 18:57:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing productive output while maintaining individual rights and dignity is the primary concern in an increasingly automated workforce system. Open source caters to this scenario and provides hyper-productive individuals with a series of resources to leverage their output and effectively provide for consumers.
Benefits
 Common knowledge pool: shared and open intellectual property which reduces &amp;ldquo;reinvention&amp;rdquo; by participants creating proprietary alternatives Non-overlapping markets: entities focus on &amp;ldquo;peripheral&amp;rdquo; markets surrounding shared core resources which encourages focus on competitive advantages Lower entry barriers: new participants can enter market rapidly as core intellectual property is openly available for use Value creation prioritization: more value is created from open resources than is captured by each individual producer Balances market forces: monopolization and perfect competition are avoided through public core resources and competitive advantage focuses Supply chain cooperation: &amp;ldquo;niche&amp;rdquo; edge producers collaborating between individual horizontal and vertical segments Adaptive technologies: common core resources with multiple contributors provides rapid updates for changing environments/requirements  Consumers benefit in this scenario of a hyper-productive minority operating in a highly automated workforce through more rapid innovation and product development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Competition</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:19:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The state is a monopoly on legislation; democracy is out best way of introducing competition.
I generally stand against any kind of monopoly and I think, in some respects, the state can be described in this way. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it abolished, but I do want it challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Economic Good</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:29:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Open source software projects are a collaborative effort. Individual developers contribute to the betterment of the project and create a publicly available, shared resource.
This model opts to create, rather than directly capture, value. Additionally, competitive markets are maintained around the project since individuals are free to take it and build products or services using it.
Since all parties share core intellectual property, competition is encouraged around the &amp;ldquo;edges&amp;rdquo; and where comparative advantages apply with some participants opting to keep these facets closed source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
