<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>politics on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in politics on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 08:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://johnforstmeier.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reputation Over Regulation</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reputation-over-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reputation-over-regulation/</guid>
      <description>Regulations on business interactions between entities can be arbitrary and typically come from a highly centralized source. Market participants must either lobby for changes (which ends up being dominated by larger financial players) or submit to regulation (which all ultimately have to anyway).
Finding ways to prioritize reputation markets, wherever feasible, may be a better alternative. Members of the given market would build a reputation through participation and staking value to have &amp;ldquo;skin in the game&amp;rdquo; and increase the cost to potential manipulators [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Brainstorm No. 2</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/political-brainstorm-no-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 08:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/political-brainstorm-no-2/</guid>
      <description>Here are some more loose ideas on simple ways to potentially improve the U.S. political system.
Ideas
 Quantifiable legislative goals: during campaigns, politicians should pledge, or maybe even be required, to set out a handful of specific policy goals with quantifiable outcomes (and preset measurement criteria). If these goals were met, assuming a successful election, they could run again after their term expires.   Goal: move elections towards data-driven performers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: The Coddling of the American Mind</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reading-the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reading-the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief summary of The Coddling of the American Mind [1] by Greg Lukianoff and Jonathan Haidt.
In short, it is a well developed, explained, and supported book that is heavily data-driven. Overall, the book is critical of the &amp;ldquo;safetyism&amp;rdquo; which is increasingly present in society and encourages building more resillient members of the broader community.
The authors highlight specific issues in how the younger generations (at the time of its writing) are being raised and present targeted solutions that parents may act upon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressive vs Expansive</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/progressive-vs-expansive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/progressive-vs-expansive/</guid>
      <description>The term &amp;ldquo;progressive&amp;rdquo; has been conflated with the word &amp;ldquo;expansive&amp;rdquo; with regards to legislative initiatives. In some ways, this is similar to the theme in Peter Thiel&amp;rsquo;s [1] book Zero to One [2].
 moving 0 -&amp;gt; 1 creates an entirely new solution moving 1 -&amp;gt; N scales an existing solution  The latter is dominant while being billed as the former in legislation. Currently, this is particularly true in two areas: minimum wage and college education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Impact</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/social-media-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/social-media-impact/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting series of questions that can be raised regarding social media listed below.
 Has the net impact of social media been positive or negative in developed nations? Has the net impact of social media been positive or negative in underdeveloped nations? If there is a difference in the answers to those questions, what causes the disparity?  These services have contributed positively and negatively to the world - identifying what distribution these contributions take would be valuable in helping to understand their proper function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulated Majorities</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/encapsulated-majorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/encapsulated-majorities/</guid>
      <description>Increased local political autonomy may reduce voting majorities to their smallest sphere of influence. This would lead to many, independent, and encapsulated majorities operating within a larger, shared population.
Several interesting points arise in this situation:
 Any tyrannical majority is confined to a small operating area In worst cases even tyrannical majorities are likely generally aligned with local interests Constituents may easily move from tyrannical majorities to elsewhere within the larger population  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Fratelli Tutti</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/reading-fratelli-tutti/</guid>
      <description>This is a breakdown of the encyclical Fratelli Tutti [1] written by Pope Francis.
The encyclical covers a wide range of topics and displays a generally more political tone while attempting to balance diverging viewpoints. Sometimes this leads to over-simplification or self-contradiction.
This note primarily discusses socio-economic subjects and reference numbers are provided for the appropriate sections of the encyclical.
   Topic Summary Comments     Culture Exporting or copying cultural models reduces national identity (#51) and different cultures are not enemies (#147).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend Competition</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/citizens-dividend-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:40:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/citizens-dividend-competition/</guid>
      <description>A non-guaranteed citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend introduces fiscal competition between political parties that are members of the dividend issuing government.
For common equity dividends the amount per share is determined by profit surplus roughly calculated as revenue minus cost. Similarly, a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend is determined by government revenue minus government cost. Given government revenue is often primarily driven by taxation, the least impactful way to increase distributions to constituents is to reduce government costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Brainstorm No. 1</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/political-brainstorm-no-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 08:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/political-brainstorm-no-1/</guid>
      <description>Below is a loose, unordered collection of &amp;ldquo;radical&amp;rdquo;, but practically implementable, ideas for the U.S. political system. These have not been evaluated for completeness - this is a braindump. However, they may be expanded on individually in the future.
Ideas
 Comprehensive Federal term limits: all Federal-level roles, including the Vice Presidency, the Senate, the House, and the Supreme Court, would be term-limited. Service could be potentially capped at eight years each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend vs UBI</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 08:15:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi/</guid>
      <description>The difference in the concepts of a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend and universal basic income (&amp;ldquo;UBI&amp;rdquo;) are laid out in the terms &amp;ldquo;dividend&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;income.&amp;rdquo;
   Feature Dividend Income     Amount Floating value based on excess revenue Fixed value determined by contract   Frequency Non-guaranteed, likely monthly/quarterly Guaranteed, determined by contract   Source Equity ownership allocates share Labor contributed under contract    These features are present in fiscal policy options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Duopoloy</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/political-duopoloy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 08:32:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/political-duopoloy/</guid>
      <description>Established political duopolies hold their members on platforms that can devolve into what can be summarized as &amp;ldquo;anti-opposing party.&amp;rdquo; Time is spent condemning the opposition&amp;rsquo;s stances without defending, or sometimes even presenting, alternatives. While there may be philosophic stratification within the dual parties, these differences are subordinate to the party positions.
Splitting these duopolies into multiple mini-parties encourages more active discourse and requires proactive engagement among colleagues when presenting and defending positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Authority Skeptic</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 08:33:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic/</guid>
      <description>Being a healthy skeptic of authority is a good thing. The keyword being healthy.
A certain amount of structure is definitely necessary to enable human socio-economic interactions. But evaluations of the structure should be constantly made:
 Evaluate the validity of the those in authority - does their position of power stem from the governed? Evaluate whether their actions fall within the purview of those in authority - are they doing what they have the capacity to do on behalf of the governed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Competition</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/democratic-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:19:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/democratic-competition/</guid>
      <description>The state is a monopoly on legislation; democracy is out best way of introducing competition.
I generally stand against any kind of monopoly and I think, in some respects, the state can be described in this way. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it abolished, but I do want it challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>