<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>politics on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in politics on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:40:20 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend Competition</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-competition-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:40:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-competition-1-0/</guid>
      <description>A non-guaranteed citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend introduces fiscal competition between political parties that are members of the dividend issuing government.
For common equity dividends the amount per share is determined by profit surplus roughly calculated as revenue minus cost. Similarly, a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend is determined by government revenue minus government cost. Given government revenue is often primarily driven by taxation, the least impactful way to increase distributions to constituents is to reduce government costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Brainstorm</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-brainstorm-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 08:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-brainstorm-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Below is a loose, unordered collection of &amp;ldquo;radical&amp;rdquo;, but practically implementable, ideas for the U.S. political system. These have not been evaluated for completeness - this is a braindump. However, they may be expanded on individually in the future.
Ideas
 Comprehensive Federal term limits: all Federal-level roles, including the Vice Presidency, the Senate, the House, and the Supreme Court, would be term-limited. Service could be potentially capped at eight years each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen&#39;s Dividend vs UBI</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 08:15:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/citizens-dividend-vs-ubi-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The difference in the concepts of a citizen&amp;rsquo;s dividend and universal basic income (&amp;ldquo;UBI&amp;rdquo;) are laid out in the terms &amp;ldquo;dividend&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;income.&amp;rdquo;
   Feature Dividend Income     Amount Floating value based on excess revenue Fixed value determined by contract   Frequency Non-guaranteed, likely monthly/quarterly Guaranteed, determined by contract   Source Equity ownership allocates share Labor contributed under contract    These features are present in fiscal policy options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Duopoloy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-duopoloy-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 08:32:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/political-duopoloy-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Established political duopolies hold their members on platforms that can devolve into what can be summarized as &amp;ldquo;anti-opposing party.&amp;rdquo; Time is spent condemning the opposition&amp;rsquo;s stances without defending, or sometimes even presenting, alternatives. While there may be philosophic stratification within the dual parties, these differences are subordinate to the party positions.
Splitting these duopolies into multiple mini-parties encourages more active discourse and requires proactive engagement among colleagues when presenting and defending positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Authority Skeptic</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 08:33:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/healthy-authority-skeptic-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Being a healthy skeptic of authority is a good thing. The keyword being healthy.
A certain amount of structure is definitely necessary to enable human socio-economic interactions. But evaluations of the structure should be constantly made:
 Evaluate the validity of the those in authority - does their position of power stem from the governed? Evaluate whether their actions fall within the purview of those in authority - are they doing what they have the capacity to do on behalf of the governed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Competition</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:19:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The state is a monopoly on legislation; democracy is out best way of introducing competition.
I generally stand against any kind of monopoly and I think, in some respects, the state can be described in this way. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it abolished, but I do want it challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
