<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>creativity on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in creativity on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 13:36:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boring Problems</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/boring-problems-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 13:36:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/boring-problems-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Boring problems often have fascinating solutions.
 This may be more or less true, and is likely dependent on personal experience, but I’ve found that boring problems have typically been left un-explored for the very reason that they’re boring. This makes it all new territory for someone venturing into it. Whatever they make to solve the problem will be entirely new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Resource Creativity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/minimal-resource-creativity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 19:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/minimal-resource-creativity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>It really seems like a minimal resource set necessitates creative solutions and efficient design.
I’m a firm believer in this. It’s sort of like building with a limited number of LEGOs: it forces you to think creatively and with imagination while also knowing intimately the number of pieces you have left and how they can work together.
 Necessity is the mother of invention.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Solution Fun</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-solution-fun-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 19:25:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-solution-fun-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Building simple solutions is fun.
This falls in with my overall philosophy of minimalism. Build lots of simple solutions and then weave them together to form something big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging Innovations</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-innovations-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 19:48:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/challenging-innovations-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Many innovations today focus on making life easier - why not build things that make life more challenging?
This sounds silly but I like the idea of building things that push us forward and challenge us physically, mentally, emotionally, spiritually, philosophically. Things like hard science and deep tech are going to really push us more than service-based innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unscripted Interactions</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/unscripted-interactions-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 09:04:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/unscripted-interactions-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Unscripted interactions are the truest demonstration of a subject matter knowledge and interest.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always preferred unscripted and unprompted discussions. I think the reason for this is because I think it shows a more genuine side of the subject.
For example, I prefer the live/unscripted entertainment bits provided by Rooster Teeth and Funhaus over the more choreographed pieces. Similarly, I think I received more thoughtful and groundbreaking insight from C.S. Lewis&amp;rsquo;s notes and letter than I have from most of his &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>