<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>law on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/law/</link>
    <description>Recent content in law on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:39:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Laws</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:39:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Laws can and should be based on immutable, moral principles, but that does not mean we need to codify and enforce every one of our morals on other people.
Sins should be easier to commit than laws should be to break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Variables</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:28:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Variables utilized in human decision making should be based in the natural world rather than arbitrary selection.
An example of this is consent. In order for consent to be actually given, the individual has to be fully cognizant of the situation and not coerced. Being cognizant would, theoretically, require a fully developed brain - although this can’t be accurately assessed on-demand and on a case-by-case basis, the age for consent (alcohol, military service, driving, sex, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Competition</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:19:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/democratic-competition-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The state is a monopoly on legislation; democracy is out best way of introducing competition.
I generally stand against any kind of monopoly and I think, in some respects, the state can be described in this way. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it abolished, but I do want it challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>