<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>law on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/tags/law/</link>
    <description>Recent content in law on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 08:32:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://johnforstmeier.com/tags/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Prison Incentives</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/private-prison-incentives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 08:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/private-prison-incentives/</guid>
      <description>Adjusting private prison contracts may better align their incentives with what the public expects from them as a service.
Prison is intended to either temporarily punish and rehabilitate or permanently remove offenders from society. The more cases that can be shifted to the former, the better.
And to do that, contracts could be based around the post-release actions of the formerly incarcerated. For example, repeat offenses, recidivism, and other lapses would negatively financially impact the prison that should be primarily focused on rehabilitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Markets</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/dangerous-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/dangerous-markets/</guid>
      <description>Financial markets should be easy to enter but difficult to actively participate in.
 Encouraging reduced barriers to entry and limitations on participation improve price discovery through the removal of arbitrary restrictions. However, a big caveat should be made to retail investors so that they&amp;rsquo;re aware that they&amp;rsquo;re very likely outgunned by the resources available to institutional investors.
Markets should be much closer to an &amp;ldquo;anything goes&amp;rdquo; model while making transaction and holdings data public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulated Majorities</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/encapsulated-majorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/encapsulated-majorities/</guid>
      <description>Increased local political autonomy may reduce voting majorities to their smallest sphere of influence. This would lead to many, independent, and encapsulated majorities operating within a larger, shared population.
Several interesting points arise in this situation:
 Any tyrannical majority is confined to a small operating area In worst cases even tyrannical majorities are likely generally aligned with local interests Constituents may easily move from tyrannical majorities to elsewhere within the larger population  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Laws</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/moral-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:39:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/moral-laws/</guid>
      <description>Laws can and should be based on immutable, moral principles, but that does not mean we need to codify and enforce every one of our morals on other people.
Sins should be easier to commit than laws should be to break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Variables</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/natural-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:28:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/natural-variables/</guid>
      <description>Variables utilized in human decision making should be based in the natural world rather than arbitrary selection.
An example of this is consent. In order for consent to be actually given, the individual has to be fully cognizant of the situation and not coerced. Being cognizant would, theoretically, require a fully developed brain - although this can’t be accurately assessed on-demand and on a case-by-case basis, the age for consent (alcohol, military service, driving, sex, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratic Competition</title>
      <link>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/democratic-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:19:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnforstmeier.com/notes/democratic-competition/</guid>
      <description>The state is a monopoly on legislation; democracy is out best way of introducing competition.
I generally stand against any kind of monopoly and I think, in some respects, the state can be described in this way. Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it abolished, but I do want it challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>