<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:39:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Laws</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:39:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/moral-laws-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Laws can and should be based on immutable, moral principles, but that does not mean we need to codify and enforce every one of our morals on other people.
Sins should be easier to commit than laws should be to break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness vs Joy</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/happiness-vs-joy-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 08:49:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/happiness-vs-joy-1-0/</guid>
      <description>There is a difference between happiness and joy.
Happiness is the emotion. Joy is the spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophic Ancestry</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/philosophic-ancestry-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:20:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/philosophic-ancestry-1-0/</guid>
      <description>While I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with most philosophic and religious traditions, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine a world that is better where Great Meteoron, Potala Palace, Shaolin Temple, Simonopetra, Blagaj Tekke, Sera Monastery, Tungnath, and many others, are silent. I really believe these monuments, and the faiths that they symbolize, to be important to our shared social fabric and our connection to our past.
The beauty and diversity of antique philosophy should be fought for and maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Variables</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:28:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Variables utilized in human decision making should be based in the natural world rather than arbitrary selection.
An example of this is consent. In order for consent to be actually given, the individual has to be fully cognizant of the situation and not coerced. Being cognizant would, theoretically, require a fully developed brain - although this can’t be accurately assessed on-demand and on a case-by-case basis, the age for consent (alcohol, military service, driving, sex, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increased Self-Direction</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/increased-self-direction-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 19:44:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/increased-self-direction-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The goal of increased individual self-direction requires providing both the individual decision-making capacity and the resources to take action with.
This is a personal goal of mine to provide both of these factors for both myself in my own life and for others in theirs. Individuals should be maximally free to self-direct and be able to utilize as many resources as possible, in many cases, to engage in productive endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Truths</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-truths-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 08:53:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/simple-truths-1-0/</guid>
      <description>The greatest truths are simple. Probably one of the most important things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from C.S. Lewis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>