<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-source on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open-source on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 18:57:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Productivity</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 18:57:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-productivity-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing productive output while maintaining individual rights and dignity is the primary concern in an increasingly automated workforce system. Open source caters to this scenario and provides hyper-productive individuals with a series of resources to leverage their output and effectively provide for consumers.
Benefits
 Common knowledge pool: shared and open intellectual property which reduces &amp;ldquo;reinvention&amp;rdquo; by participants creating proprietary alternatives Non-overlapping markets: entities focus on &amp;ldquo;peripheral&amp;rdquo; markets surrounding shared core resources which encourages focus on competitive advantages Lower entry barriers: new participants can enter market rapidly as core intellectual property is openly available for use Value creation prioritization: more value is created from open resources than is captured by each individual producer Balances market forces: monopolization and perfect competition are avoided through public core resources and competitive advantage focuses Supply chain cooperation: &amp;ldquo;niche&amp;rdquo; edge producers collaborating between individual horizontal and vertical segments Adaptive technologies: common core resources with multiple contributors provides rapid updates for changing environments/requirements  Consumers benefit in this scenario of a hyper-productive minority operating in a highly automated workforce through more rapid innovation and product development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Economic Good</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:29:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/open-source-economic-good-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Open source software projects are a collaborative effort. Individual developers contribute to the betterment of the project and create a publicly available, shared resource.
This model opts to create, rather than directly capture, value. Additionally, competitive markets are maintained around the project since individuals are free to take it and build products or services using it.
Since all parties share core intellectual property, competition is encouraged around the &amp;ldquo;edges&amp;rdquo; and where comparative advantages apply with some participants opting to keep these facets closed source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
