<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biotech on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/biotech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in biotech on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/biotech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Bad Blood</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-bad-blood/</guid>
      <description>This piece is on Bad Blood [1] by John Carreyrou [2].
I was familiar with the story of Elizabeth Holmes [3] and her company Theranos [4] but the book provided greater insight into how she interacted with people regarding her work.
It is unclear whether her extreme focus on &amp;ldquo;her mission&amp;rdquo; was a manipulative effort or actual self-denial; her actions could support both positions.
There are many instances of Holmes legally pursuing whistleblowers and publicly attacking external detractors - essentially anyone threatening the positive perception of Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharmaceuticals As Software</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/pharma-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 08:25:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/pharma-software/</guid>
      <description>Some characteristics of pharmaceuticals make them comparable to software. Basically software and pharmaceuticals have:
 high development costs low distribution costs  For example, both require a large, upfront resource investment in research and composition. After initial R&amp;amp;D expenses, both are relatively easily manufactured and distributed at scale.
Knowing this, pharmaceuticals may be well placed to leverage wide-reaching treatments while reducing healthcare costs. Additionally, with precision medicine [1], highly-focused solutions can be developed or even compounded on-demand for individual use to increase effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>