<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>logic on John Forstmeier</title>
    <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/logic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in logic on John Forstmeier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 08:45:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://forstmeier.github.io/tags/logic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading: Cynical Theories</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 08:45:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/reading-cynical-theories-1-0/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief summary of takeaways from reading Cynical Theories [1] by James Lindsay and Helen Pluckrose of &amp;ldquo;grievance studies affair&amp;rdquo; [2] infamy.
Overall, the book does an excellent job outlining the history of the overarching worldview termed &amp;ldquo;critical theory&amp;rdquo; as well as presenting a number of succinct counter arguments against it.
The most interesting topics covered are the breakdowns of the individual fields within the broader philosophy.
Tracing specific ancestries and outlining each field&amp;rsquo;s current form and emphasis within the umbrella is highly valuable; it highlights both specific facets that the laity may more successfully understand and grapple with as well as potentially destructive tensions between the fields making up &amp;ldquo;critical theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Variables</title>
      <link>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:28:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://forstmeier.github.io/notes/natural-variables-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Variables utilized in human decision making should be based in the natural world rather than arbitrary selection.
An example of this is consent. In order for consent to be actually given, the individual has to be fully cognizant of the situation and not coerced. Being cognizant would, theoretically, require a fully developed brain - although this can’t be accurately assessed on-demand and on a case-by-case basis, the age for consent (alcohol, military service, driving, sex, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>